All right.
Exciting night. We'll just jump right
into it.
>> Any questions?
>> Hey, frustrating for both you and Darren
with Bailey. I mean, obviously the the
raging debate was, you know, you know,
the experience and and the production
versus the the the potential and
whatnot. Can you talk a little bit about
what stood out with Bailey for you guys?
>> Yeah, I would say this, both of those
guys um cuz we're talking about those
two guys are really good players. Um,
listen, Arll is going to have a really
good um, career in this league, but when
you just continue to evaluate those
guys, we just felt like Bailey fit us
better when it comes to he's a 6'4, 255b
man with 34 inch arms that has ton of
production in college. Um, listen, we
looked at all those things and like he
fits us.
>> Was I'm sorry. Go ahead.
>> No, no, go ahead. Was Sadi one of those
value picks where you stick to the value
board and you go, "Wow, we can't pass
this."
>> Yeah, absolutely. Sadique was a player
that obviously we studied, spent a lot
of time on and valued as an offensive
weapon. And when he was there, it was
really a no-brainer for us just to add
another weapon to the offense. And and
Frank's got a great vision for the
player and how we can use him in
multiple ways and get in 12 personnel
and do different things and just use him
as another weapon and and make it tough
on the defense. How how um how rare is
it to have a guy like that who could
stretch the field but also is a willing
blocker too. It's a D.
>> Yeah, that's one thing that like I think
a lot of people are surprised. You you
assume you look at the tag, right? He's
240 lbs. He ran 439. Oh, this is just
going to be an F. He's going to be out
there split. When this guy's in line, he
he's a he's a good blocker. Not just a
serviceable blocker. He's a good
blocker. And and you said it that just
adds to his value and versatility. He
he's he's going to be able to uh we're
going to be able to dictate uh as far as
the defense is concerned on what are you
going to play. You can be in base or you
going to be in nickel and he brings that
value to us. Man, there are so many
positions that he can play for us. Um
that's going to make us be able to open
up the offense, you know, and and Frank
has a really really good vision uh for
this player. So, man, we're looking for
I'm looking forward to going against
this player, you know, during training
camp. So, it'll be fun. you guys you
guys obviously felt like you had enough
like you said information to cancel the
the visit with David.
curious like what what was it about your
conversations with him over the course
of this process where you thought okay
we're very comfortable with them and the
idea of taking him
>> well obviously at the combine uh we had
conversations with him and that was only
20 minutes but when you go to uh his pro
day and be able to go out to eat dinner
with them man you could really dig deep
into who he is as a person and man
listen we had got a lot of information
about who he is and then we had guys
from from Stanford you know that that
coach for us and they know about the guy
so um We felt really comfortable with uh
drafting the guy, too.
>> I also had a really good Zoom call with
the player as well, so we had multiple
touch points and felt really good about
it.
>> A lot of people talk about Bailey's uh
get off, you know, his Twitch and so
forth. I'm wonder how do you evaluate
that trade? Like how how good is it and
how does that fit into the kind of
defense you want?
>> Well, just first step quickness and
that's obvious when you watch the tape.
um the way he's able to beat tackles
around the edge, but he don't take him
for a guy that could just like rush with
speed around the edge, man. There are
several long arm, there are several
power, um things that he's done, you
know, within within uh his game that
allows him to be able to show that he
can rush with power. So, um listen,
we're going to try to unlock everything
that he can. I mean, obviously, we have
some really good coaches that's going to
be able to help him. Um and we're really
excited about that. We were excited
about all three of the players that we
got.
>> How important was it to to address the
pass catching position when you know I
think everybody made a big deal about
nothing happened in free agency at that
spot. Now you got two today. How
important was that?
>> It was definitely important, but we were
still stacking the board with players
that we think can help us and their
overall value. Talking about Sadi and
just as an overall weapon and he was
there and we think this is great value.
dad to the offense and then Omar Cooper
was a guy that we had good grades on and
when we saw him there towards the end an
opportunity to give up a comp fifth pick
179 to get back up and get the fifth
year option just make sure we got our
guy we felt really good about that again
to add another weapon a guy that's got
rack strong hands can insert block has a
little versatility to play inside and
outside so feel really good about those
those two additions for the offense
>> here's what also is critical what's
critical about um those three players is
they come from winning programs also.
So, when you get a chance to bring that
into your locker room, um, man, it
speaks volumes. I mean, Omar, we all
seen against Penn State when he made the
the game-winning catch. Um, man, you saw
the things that that Bailey did as far
as the force fumbles and things like
that. Uh, you saw Sadique and his rag,
man. All those guys has done something
within their career. They either won the
game, they take over a game, but they
come from winning programs and that was
huge to be able to get guys like that.
Darren, you the assumption was was all
along from many people was you want you
were going to come out of here with an
edge rusher and potentially a receiver.
The fact that you got Sadi in there with
these three. Can you things have fallen
any better because the receivers kind of
slid down a little bit for a while, you
know?
>> Yeah, it's exciting. We're definitely
happy with the way it fell. There's no
doubt about that because we know we the
more weapons we have, you know, the
better chance we have on offense and
just to do different things like coach
mentioned, you know, you can give
defenses problems with, you know, the
versatility these guys that we're
adding.
>> Did you get any when you were on for
this number two pick? Any calls?
>> Didn't get any calls. Had a lot of
conversations leading up to it, but
nothing serious and didn't get any
calls.
>> Aaron, how um how is Bailey against the
run and how
>> how was he against the run?
>> Three down. Yeah, I I think he did a
good job when you watch him uh at Tech.
Um listen, there are some things he got
to improve on just like any player
that's coming in. But man, listen, we
have four guys, four edges. Well,
actually more than that, but with those
four guys that we uh we have on the
team, man, they're going to be to cause
some damage for us. Um so, I'm looking
forward to coaching those guys. Again,
uh we have to make sure everybody comes
in understand exactly what to do with
the scheme, but he's going to fit right
in with us.
>> What What do you think about the depth
of the tight end room? I mean, you
talked you thinking Mason was a huge
year
>> and now you went out and got
>> Yeah. Yeah. And and and and Darren just
said it, man. Just to be able to have
another weapon on our offense that gives
Gino a chance to be a point guard to be
able to deliver the ball to these guys
is huge. And anytime you can build your
tight end room the way that we have, it
allows you to get in different type of
packages, but be able to force the
defense to, okay, so what are you going
to do now? And if you get a nickel, we
get a chance to run the ball. You get in
base, then we get a chance to throw it.
So, man, it's um it's gonna be exciting,
you know, to have him and the rest of
those tight ends we have on the game at
the same time.
>> What uh for AG?
>> Yep.
>> You don't see teams get three first
round picks that often now. I It did
happen here four years ago, 22, but
really it's only happened like maybe
three, four times in team history. What
from a big tick picture standpoint, what
does it mean? You're trying to get this
rebuild going here just to get these
three guys. What does it do for the
acceleration program? I I think it's
something that um that I've talked about
before is when you have targets, you
identify guys you like uh you love, you
love, you go get them. And that's
exactly what we did today. And anytime
you can bring guys with a winning
background on your team, that only helps
the morale of your team. Um, so there's
a lot of things that go into that, but
man, to get three first round picks, um,
and the caliber of guys that we got,
the, um, the personality, the mentality,
the football character, all those
things, um, are huge, you know, bringing
those guys on our team.
>> Was there a maturity level in those
three guys that was like a common thing
there? Because we heard about, you know,
David and how how advanced he is. I
think he graduated in three years,
something. Was there a maturity level
you saw?
>> No doubt. I mean, I know I felt that
when I met all of those those players
that that we're talking about here that
you definitely felt a mature level, a
professionalism to those guys, which is
good. You feel good about that.
>> D, when did you know Bailey was the guy?
>> We had discussions all the time leading
up to it, right? And we were never going
to make a decision until we had to. You
know, I I think the last few days we
really it started to crystallize for us
and become, you know, pretty concrete.
we knew, but we never want to make a
decision until we absolutely had to. So,
um, it was in the last few days we had
some good discussions.
>> Take a couple more.
>> So, what was the thinking in cancing the
visit? Was there some poker? We playing
a little poker there?
>> No, it wasn't. It was, like I said
earlier, there was a lot of different
reasons. We were juggling really all 30
of them. We had good touch points as
coach mentioned. I had a great zoom with
him. Didn't feel the need.
>> Did you not want to make him fly cross
country?
>> No, he was he he was bouncing around. He
would have been fine. plan in but yeah
it wasn't anything like I mentioned
before.
>> Okay, thanks everyone.